Donald Hyde and Mary Hyde Eccles Autograph Collection (MS Hyde 10): Guide.
Donald Hyde and Mary Hyde Eccles Autograph Collection,
- Mathias, Thomas James, 1754?-1835. Autograph letter, signed, Middle Scotland Yard, Whitehall [London] to [Dawson Turner] 1813 Sept. 28., (464); 1s.
- Maty, Matthew, 1718-1776. Printed form, signed, British Museum [London] to Andrew Coltee Ducarel, 1761 Aug. 16., (465); 2s.
  Thanking Ducarel on behalf of the British Museum for his gift of A Series of Above Two Hundred Anglo-Gallic, or Norman and Aquitain Coins. With envelope.
- Maurice, Frederick Denison, 1805-1872. Autograph letter, signed, Working Men's College (London, England), to unidentified recipient, 1854 Nov. 9., (466); 1s.
  Offers thanks for proposal. Written nine days after the first classes began at Working Men's College.
- Maurice, Thomas, 1754-1824. Autograph letter, signed, British Museum [London] to Christopher Idle of Adelphi Terrace [London] [1804] Aug. 18., (467); 1s.
  Seeks to pay a debt with a set of his publications.
- Mazarin, Jules, 1602-1661. Autograph letter, signed, Châlons-sur-Marne (France), to Éléonore-Catherine-Fébronie de Berg, duchesse de Bouillon, 1653 Nov. 17., (468); 1s.
  Concerning the demolition of the walls of Tartas (France). In French.
- Melanchthon, Philipp, 1497-1560. Autograph letter, signed, Wittenberg (Saxony-Anhalt, Germany), to "Theodoro concionatori ecclesia" of Nuremberg (Germany), 1537 [May 10] Ascension., (469); 1s.
  In Latin.
- Melmoth, William, 1710?-1799. Autograph letter, signed, Bath (England), to [Joshua?] Sharpe of Lincoln's Inn [London] 1777 Feb. 15., (470); 1s.
  Requests assistance in securing a lease for a tenant.
- Melville, Henry Dundas, Viscount, 1742-1811. Letter, signed, Whitehall (London), to [John Graves Simcoe] Lieutenant Governor of Lower Canada, 1792 Dec. 8., (471); 1s.
  Concerning the danger of hostilities with France.
- Melville, Henry Dundas, Viscount, 1742-1811. 3 autograph letters, signed, London and Edinburgh (Scotland), to Sir George Yonge, 1786-1791. Mar. 18., (472); 3s.
  The 1786 Mar. 18 letter announces the resignation of Mark Pringle as Judge Advocate of Scotland, and recommends Charles Hope, Lord Granton to take his place. The [1790] Oct. 17 letter sends names of three candidates for independent military companies. The 1791 Dec.1 letter recommends Capt. Burnett for a promotion.
- Melville, Henry Dundas, Viscount, 1742-1811. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to unidentified recipient, [1798 Feb.] 25, Friday., (473); 1s.
  Will accept the ensigncy, apparently on behalf of a Mr. Hamilton.
- Mercier, Charles-André. Bill of exchange: document, signed, [no place] 1789 Mar. 2., (474); 1s.
  Order to George Robinson to pay Sir Robert Herries.
- Mercier, Charles-André. Receipt: autograph document, signed, [no place] 1788 Oct. 25., (475); 1s.
  Receipt to George Robinson Co. for copyright to A Journey through the Crimea to Constantinople by Elizabeth Craven, Baroness Craven.
- Mill, John Stuart, 1806-1873. Autograph letter, signed, "J.V.", to [John?] Robertson, [ca. 1851?] Saturday., (476); 1s.
  Concerning Robertson's article on Edward Bulwer Lytton, Baron Lytton, submitted while Mill was serving as guest editor for W.E. (William Edward) Hickson's Westminster Review. Mentions Alexander Bain (1818-1903).
- Millar, Andrew, 1707-1768. Receipt: autograph document, signed, [no place] 1753 May 23., (477); 1s.
  Receipt to Robert Dodsley for his share of Jonas Hanway's An Historical Account of the British Trade over the Caspian Sea.
- Miller, Philip, 1691-1771. Autograph letter, signed, Chelsea (London), to unidentified recipient, 1758 Sept. 18., (478); 1s.
  Concerning botanical matters.
- Minto, Gilbert Elliot, Earl of, 1751-1814. Autograph letter, signed, Bastia (Italy), to Sir Thomas Trigge, 1795 Sept. 19., (479); 2s.
  Concerning custom duties on wine.
- Montesquieu, Charles de Secondat, baron de, 1689-1755. Autograph letter, signed, Paris, to Filippo Venuti, 1749 Aug. 9., (480); 1s.
- Montrose, James Graham, Duke of, 1755-1836. Autograph letter, signed, Grosvenor Square [London] to William Henry Cavendish-Bentinck, Duke of Portland, 1799 Feb. 7., (481); 1s.
  Concerning the Stirling militia.
- Moore, Edward, 1712-1757. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to Rev. J. Ward, [1748 or 1753?] Tuesday., (482); 1s.
  Mentions rehearsals with David Garrick. Garrick starred in two of Moore's plays, The Foundling and The Gamester.
- Moore, John, 1729-1802. Autograph letter, signed, Clarges Street [London] to William Strahan, 1780 Feb. 1., (483); 1s.
  Concerning the publication of A View of Society and Manners in France, Switzerland, and Germany.
- Moore, John, 1729-1802. Autograph letter, signed, Clifford Street [London] to Strahan Cadell, 1789 July 10., (484); 1s.
  Concerning publication of Zeluco: Various Views of Human Nature.
- Moore, John, 1729-1802. Receipt: autograph document, signed, [no place] 1779 July 13., (485); 1s.
  Receipt to Strahan Cadell for copyright to A View of Society and Manners in France, Switzerland, and Germany.
  - Recto
  - Verso
- Moore, John, 1729-1802. Receipt: autograph document, signed, [no place] 1794 June 7., (486); 1s.
  Receipt to T. (Thomas) Cadell for the eighth edition of A View of Society and Manners in France, Switzerland, and Germany, per agreement with Strahan Cadell.
- Moore, Thomas, 1779-1852. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to [James] Carpenter, [before 1812], (487); 1s.
  Asking for address cards reading "33 Bury Street."
- More, Martha, 1746?-1819. 6 autograph letters, signed, to Thomas Sedgwick Whalley, 1800-1819., (488); 6s.
  Many letters discuss her sister Hannah More. Three undated letters circa 1800, two undated letters not before 1812, and one dated 1819 July 5.
- Mount Edgcumbe, Emma Edgcumbe, Countess of, 1729-1807. Autograph letter, signed, London, to Mr. Sénégas [?] 1784 Nov. 30., (489); 1s.
  Seeks assistance in finding a cook.
- Murphy, Arthur, 1727-1805. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to George Colman, [1772 Dec.?] Friday., (490); 2s.
  Concerning the scheduling of two competing Murphy plays, probably his tragedy Alzuma and his comedy Know Your Own Mind. Mentions David Garrick and Elizabeth Hartley.
- Murphy, Arthur, 1727-1805. Autograph letter, signed, Hammersmith Terrace [London] to Cecilia Thrale [Mostyn] 1795 Mar. 16., (491); 1s.
  Concerning his plans to visit Streatham Park [London]
- Murray, William. Autograph letter, signed, Clarendon Hotel [London] to Mr. Brevort, Esq., [1802 or 1813] May 19, Wednesday., (492); 1s.
  Invites Brevort to accompany him to a party at the home of Lady Amelia Ramsay Campbell.
- Musgrave, Richard, Sir, 1757?-1818. Autograph letter, signed, Dublin (Ireland), to unidentified recipient, 1802 Sept. 20., (493); 1s.
  Concerning his Memoirs of the Different Rebellions in Ireland.
- Mylne, Robert, 1734-1811. Autograph letter, signed, Wormleybury, Hertfordshire [England] to unidentified recipient, [1767] May 18., (494); 1s.
  Offering thanks for help with election.
- Nairne, Edward, 1726-1806. Autograph letter, signed, London, to Sir William Hamilton, 1774 Aug. 12., (495); 2s.
  Describes electrical experiments, and his discussion with Benjamin Franklin.
- Napier, Alexander, 1814-1887. Autograph letter, signed, Holkham Vicarage, Norfolk (England), to [Samuel] Timmins, 1884 Aug. 9., (496); 1s.
  Thanks for praise of new edition of The Life of Samuel Johnson, LL.D.
- Nares, Robert, 1753-1829. Autograph letter, signed, British Museum [London] to Sir James Bland Burges, 1805 Jan. 9., (497); 1s.
  Describes actor William Henry West Betty.
- Newcastle, Henry Fiennes Pelham-Clinton, Duke of, 1720-1794 (then Earl of Lincoln). Order to pay: document, signed, [no place] 1763 July 15., (498); 1s.
  Pay warrant to deputy chamberlains Abraham Farley and John Barlase, also signed by George Grenville and Robert Henley, Earl of Northington.
- Newcastle, Thomas Pelham-Holles, Duke of, 1693-1768. Autograph letter, signed, Claremont [Surrey, England] to unidentified recipient, [1761 Aug. 7?] Friday., (499); 1s.
  Apparently recommending Robert Hay Drummond, Bishop of Salisbury, as the next Archbishop of York.
- Newcastle, Thomas Pelham-Holles, Duke of, 1693-1768. Order to pay: document, signed, St. James's [London] 1755 Jan. 28., (500); 1s.
  Order upon the Royal Treasury for secret service. Also signed by Henry Bilson-Legge.
- Newman, John Henry, 1801-1890. Autograph letter, signed, The Oratory [London] to Charles Félix Audley, 1864 Dec. 26., (501); 1s.
  Concerning the French translation of his Apologia.
- Newman, John Henry, 1801-1890. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to unidentified recipient, 1885 Oct. 26., (502); 1s.
  Agrees with the statement of cardinal Henry Edward Manning.
- Newton, A. Edward (Alfred Edward), 1864-1940. Dr. Samuel Johnson engraved in mezzotint: autograph manuscript, signed, [no place] [ca. 1925], (503); 4s.
  Newton's text for a prospectus. With typescript transcript, and a copy of the printed prospectus. In a blue slipcase.
  *2003JM-207.
- Newton, Isaac, Sir, 1642-1727. Receipt: document, signed, [no place] 1713 Apr. 13., (504); 1s.
  Receipt for annuity, made out to teller Francis Robartes. Also signed by witness John Francis Fauquier.
- Newton, John, 1725-1807. Autograph letter, signed, Olney (England), to E. (Edward) Dilly, 1769 Sept. 2., (505); 1s.
  Concerning publishing arrangements for Newton's A Review of Ecclesiastical History.
- Newton, John, 1725-1807. Autograph letter, signed, "No. 6", to Ambrose Serle, 1795 July 28., (506); 1s.
  Describes himself as possibly the oldest Methodist clergyman in England.
- Nicol, G. (George). Autograph letter, signed, Strand [London] to John Hoole, 1784 Dec. 13., (507); 1s.
  Concerning efforts to sell copyright to the works of Samuel Johnson, to help support him in his final illness. Johnson died later that day.
  - Recto
  - Verso
- Noble, Mark, 1754-1827. Mrs. Piozzi: manuscript, signed, [between 1821-1827], (507a); 1s.
  A short biographical sketch and pedigree of Hester Lynch Piozzi.
  The text is not in Noble's hand, although the manuscript bears his signature.
- North, Frederick, Lord, 1732-1792. Autograph letter, signed, Bushy Park [London] to Wills Hill, Marquis of Downshire (then Viscount Hillsborough), 1781 Jan. 4., (508); 1s.
  Desires royal confirmation of Sir John Macpherson's appointment in Calcutta (India).
- Northcote, James, 1746-1831. Autograph letter, signed, Argyll Street [London] to Henry Colburn,; British and Foreign Library [London] [between 1806-1822] Tuesday., (509); 1s.
  Letter of introduction for an engraver.
- Northcote, James, 1746-1831. Autograph letter, signed, Argyll Street [London] to Sir R. (Richard) Phillips, [1815 July 14] Friday., (510); 1s.
  Can supply a drawing of the late Samuel Whitbread.
- Northcote, James, 1746-1831. Autograph letter, signed, Argyll Street [London] to John Young (1755-1825), 1819 Apr. 28., (511); 1s.
  Declines invitation: "I have not dined out of my own house these two years."
- Northcote, James, 1746-1831. Fable, the ant and the bee: autograph manuscript, [no place] [18--], (512); 1s.
  Manuscript poem.
- Nourse, J. (John), d. 1780. Autograph letter, signed, London, to Jacobus Wetstein, 1765 Nov. 22., (513); 1s.
- Nourse, J. (John), d. 1780. Account: manuscript document, [no place] 1767 Feb. 17., (514); 1s.
  Accounts with Richard Hett concerning corrections to Richard Orme's History of the Military Transactions of the British Nation in Indostan, dating back to 1764 Dec. 10.
- O'Conor, Charles, 1710-1791. This is the abridgment for confessorum: autograph manuscript, [no place] [17--], (515); 1s.
  Explanation of an Irish Gaelic word.
- Oliver, William, 1695-1764. Autograph letter draft, signed, Bath (England), to Alexander Pope, 1740 Mar. 19., (516); 1s.
  Thanks for The Works of Alexander Pope.
- Opie, John, 1761-1807. Autograph note, signed, [no place] to Mr. Frank, [17--?] Tuesday., (517); 1s.
  Setting plans to visit.
- Orme, Robert, 1728-1801. 3 autograph letters, signed, to F. (Francis) Wingrave, 1782-1794., (518); 3s.
  Two 1782 Oct. letters offer corrections to proofs. A letter dated 1794 Aug. 5 orders a pamphlet.
- Ormonde, Charles Butler, Duke of, 1671-1758 (then Earl of Arran). Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to unidentified recipient, [17--], (519); 1s.
  Asks an unnamed duke to secure officer commissions from the ranks of the new troops.
  Partial transcript in Adam, 9.
- Orrery, Charles Boyle, Earl of, 1676-1731. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to unidentified recipient, 1713 Aug. 12., (520); 1s.
  Concerning the military rank of William Cecil.
- Orrery, John Boyle, Earl of, 1707-1762. Bond: document, signed, [no place] 1751 Oct. 9., (521); 1s.
  Bond from Orrery and his son Charles Boyle to Robert French.
- Osborn, John, d. 1775. Autograph letter, signed, Turville Court [Bath, England] to J. (John) Nourse, 1771 July 28., (522); 1s.
  Concerning a settlement with [Joseph?] Cooper. With manuscript transcript in unknown hand of a letter from Cooper to Osborn, 1771 July 24, concerning the printing of the General Evening Post (London).
- Oughton, James Adolphus, Sir, 1719-1780. Autograph letter, signed, London, to Robert Barrie, surgeon's mate, Pensacola, Florida, 1767 Feb. 9., (523); 1s.
  Concerning Barrie's desire to remove to Antigua.
- Oxford, Edward Harley, Earl of, 1689-1741. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to Rev. Dr. Williams, 1735 Feb. 5., (524); 2s.
  Concerning negotiations. With part of cover.
- Oxford, Robert Harley, Earl of, 1661-1724. Bond: document, signed, [no place] 1714 Dec. 24., (525); 1s.
  Bond to William Hewer. Includes payment history, 1717-1723.
- Palmerston, Henry John Temple, Viscount, 1784-1865. Autograph letter, signed, Stanhope Street [London] to Sarah Bayley, 1834 Nov. 1., (526); 1s.
  Cannot offer a position to her son.
- Palmerston, Henry John Temple, Viscount, 1784-1865. Order (military document): document, signed, War Office [London] 1817 Nov. 22., (527); 1s.
  Order for unidentified soldier to be stationed at Westminster (London).
- Palmerston, Henry Temple, Viscount, 1739-1802. Promissory note: document, signed, Madeira (Madeira Islands), 1771 Aug. 20., (528); 1s.
  Note from George Brydges Rodney, Baron Rodney to Scott Pringle, endorsed twice by Palmerston.
- Paoli, Pasquale, 1725-1807. Ribbons: textile, [not before 1762], (529); 2 items
  Silk embroidered with patriotic inscription "Vive P. de Paoli e la Liberte" and a Moor's head (Paoli's emblem of Corsica). Includes one emblem and one uncut strip of five emblems.
- Parker, Sackville, 1707-1796. Autograph letter, signed, Oxford (England), to J. (John) Nourse, 1740 July 1., (530); 1s.
  Order for books.
- Parr, Samuel, 1747-1825. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to Miss de Benliese [?] of 4 Coleman Street, Ruislip [London] 1817 Feb. 2., (531); 1s.
  Financial matters.
- Parr, Samuel, 1747-1825. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to [Martin] Davy, [1814] June 27., (532); 1s.
  Concerning the University of Cambridge.
- Parr, Samuel, 1747-1825. Autograph letter, signed, [Warwick, England] to Adam Fytche, of Cambridge (England), 1819 Mar. 30., (533); 1s.
- Parr, Samuel, 1747-1825. Letter, signed, Hatton [London] to Daniel Jarvis, of Margate, Kent (England), 1823 Sept. 26., (534); 1s.
  Discusses his close acquaintance with Thomas Sheridan; mentions Samuel Johnson and David Garrick.
- Parr, Samuel, 1747-1825. Autograph letter, signed, Caius College [Cambridge, England] to Rev. Mr. William Philips of Eling, Hampshire, [1811] March 17, Sunday., (535); 1s.
  Concerning the election of William Frederick, Duke of Gloucester, as chancellor of the University of Cambridge.
- Payne, John, d. 1787. Autograph letter, signed, Paternoster Row [London] to [Robert Dodsley?] 1752 Dec. 11., (536); 1s.
  Concerning competition between Samuel Johnson's Adventurer and a periodical published by Dodsley.
- Payne, John, d. 1787. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to [Joseph Warton?] [1754] Feb. 2., (537); 1s.
  Concerning authorship of issues of the Adventurer. Mentions Samuel Johnson twice.
- Pearson, John Batteridge, 1749-1808. Autograph letter, signed, Lichfield (England), to James Boswell, 1784 Apr. 2., (538); 1s.
  Has sent twelve letters written by Samuel Johnson to his step-daughter Lucy Porter, and grants Boswell publication rights.
- Pendleton, William. Petition: autograph draft document, Peterborough, Northamptonshire (England), 1732 Feb. 19., (539); 1s.
  Partial draft petition to the Lord High Chancellor [Peter King, Lord King] concerning guardianship of Samuel Pendleton, "a Lunatick."
- Perreau, Robert, d. 1776. Account: autograph document, signed, [no place] 1768 Jan. 30., (540); 1s.
  Account with Mr. Stafford for apothecary charges from 1766 Mar. to May, receipted as paid on 1768 Jan. 30 by Perreau.
- Pindar, Peter, 1738-1819 (writing as John Wolcot). Autograph letter, signed, Cornwall (England), to [Sir Richard] Phillips, 1806 Jan. 5., (541); 1s.
  Social letter.
- Pindar, Peter, 1738-1819 (writing as John Wolcot). Autograph letter, signed, Delancy Place, Camden (London), to John Walker (d. 1817), 1804 Apr. 19., (542); 1s.
  Describing efforts to gather subscriptions for his next book.
- Pindar, Peter, 1738-1819. To Mitchel, the miniature-painter; a familiar epistle: manuscript transcript, [London] [1804 Aug. 9], (543); 4 leaves, sewn with string
  Manuscript transcript poem in an unknown hand, addressed to Mr. Mitchel [Thomas Mitchell?] miniature painter, 64 Jermyn Street, St. James's [London]
- Piozzi, Gabriele Mario, 1740-1809. Autograph letter, signed, Streatham Park [London] to [John?] Lloyd, 1795 May 13., (544); 1s.
  Retained copy. Concerning a financial settlement, possibly with Lloyd's client Thomas Pennant.
  See Edward A. and Lillian D. Bloom, eds., The Piozzi Letters (Newark, Del.: University of Delaware Press, 1989) 2, 264.
- Piozzi, Gabriele Mario, 1740-1809. Typescript transcript letter, [Streatham Park, London] to Cecilia Thrale Mostyn, 1795 July 15., (545); 3s.
  Family news; mentions Sarah Siddons. A portion of the original letter was in Italian, but the entirety is presented here in English translation. Includes a postscript by Arthur Murphy. The location of the original letter unknown.
- Piozzi, Gabriele Mario, 1740-1809. Autograph note, signed, [no place] to Joseph Fitzwilliam Vandercom, 1794 Mar. 7., (546); 1s.
  Concerning rents due to Piozzi at Crowmarsh, Oxfordshire, England by Thomas Lovegrove.
  See Edward A. and Lillian D. Bloom, eds., The Piozzi Letters (Newark, Del.: University of Delaware Press, 1989) 1, 369.
- Piozzi, Gabriele Mario, 1740-1809. Advertising card: printed document, [London] 1777 Apr. 18., (547); 1s.
  Advertisement for a benefit concert of vocal and instrumental music being given for Piozzi.
- Piozzi, Gabriele Mario, 1740-1809. Application: manuscript transcript, Bath (England), 1784 July 8., (548); 1s.
  Application to marry Hester Lynch Piozzi (then Hester Lynch Thrale). Transcript by clerk N. Morgan.
- Planta, Joseph, 1744-1827. Autograph letter, signed, British Museum [London] to unidentified recipient, 1807 Oct. 6., (549); 1s.
  Thanks for books. In French.
- Playfair, James, 1738-1819. Autograph letter, signed, [Dundee, Scotland] to William Strahan, [ca. 1784 Mar. 24], (550); 1s.
  Wants Samuel Johnson's name on his subscription list, possibly for his System of Chronology.
- Plunket, William Conyngham Plunket, Baron, 1764-1854. Autograph letter, signed, Dublin (Ireland), to unidentified recipient, 1821 Dec. 26., (551); 1s.
  Concerning the appointment of Charles Watkin Williams Wynn.
- Pocock, Robert, 1760-1830. Autograph letter, signed, [Gravesend, Kent, England] to James Lackington Co., 1801 Aug. 16., (552); 1s.
  Ordering books.
- Pococke, Richard, 1704-1765. Autograph draft letter, signed, Bristol (England), to his mother [Elizabeth Milles Pococke] 1750 Nov. 2., (553); 3s.
  Offers a detailed description of Bath (England) and surrounding towns.
- Polwhele, Richard, 1760-1838. Autograph letter, signed, Polwhele near Truro [Cornwall, England] to Alaric Alexander Watts, 1822 June 12., (554); 2s.
  Recuperating at Polwhele vicarage. Includes cover.
- Pope, Alexander, 1688-1744. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to [Samuel] Buckley, [17--] Monday., (555); 1s.
  Accepting invitation.
- Pope, Alexander, 1688-1744. Autograph note, [no place] to [Jonathan Richardson] 1743 [1742] Aug. 5, Thursday., (556); 1s.
  George Sherburn, ed., The Correspondence of Alexander Pope (Oxford: Clarendon Press, 1956) IV, 409.
- Pope, Alexander, 1688-1744. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to Thomas Wentworth, Earl of Strafford, [1725 June], (557); 3s.
  Concerning a proposed monument to Sir Godfrey Kneller. With typescript transcript.
  George Sherburn, ed., The Correspondence of Alexander Pope (Oxford: Clarendon Press, 1956) II, 300-301.
- Pope, Alexander, 1688-1744. Autograph letter, signed, Twitnam [Twickenham, London] to Thomas Wentworth, Earl of Strafford, [1725] July 6., (558); 6s.
  Describing a conversation with Sir Godfrey Kneller on his deathbed. With typescript transcript.
  George Sherburn, ed., The Correspondence of Alexander Pope (Oxford: Clarendon Press, 1956) II, 308-310.
- Pope, Alexander, 1688-1744. Autograph letter, signed, Twitnam [Twickenham, London] to Thomas Wentworth, Earl of Strafford, [1725] Aug. 12., (559); 4s.
  George Sherburn, ed., The Correspondence of Alexander Pope (Oxford: Clarendon Press, 1956) II, 313-314.
- Pope, Alexander, 1688-1744. Autograph letter, signed, Twitenham [Twickenham, London] to Thomas Wentworth, Earl of Strafford, [1725] Oct. 5., (560); 4s.
  Concerning a proposed monument to Sir Godfrey Kneller, and Pope's religious practice. With typescript transcript.
  George Sherburn, ed., The Correspondence of Alexander Pope (Oxford: Clarendon Press, 1956) II, 327-329.
- Pope, Alexander, 1688-1744. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to [Jacob] Tonson [d. 1735?] [ca. 1725?] Friday., (561); 1s.
  May relate to efforts to secure royal patronage for Pope's edition of Shakespeare.
  Not found in George Sherburn's The Correspondence of Alexander Pope.
- Pope, Alexander, 1688-1744. Receipt: document, signed, [no place] [between 1714-1720], (562); 1s.
  Receipt to Thomas Southcotte for a subscription to Pope's translation of the Iliad.
- Porson, Richard, 1759-1808. Autograph letter, signed, Essex Court, No. 5 [London] to Rev. George A. Browne,; Trinity College, Cambridge, 1805 Feb. 4., (563); 2s.
  Offers comments on an epitaph. With cover.
- Porson, Richard, 1759-1808. Bought for the London Institution Library: autograph document, [no place] 1808 May., (564); 1s.
  List of 21 books purchased for the London Institution, with prices.
- Porson, Richard, 1759-1808. List: autograph document, signed, [no place] 1806 May 24., (565); 1s.
  List of clothing.
- Porson, Richard, 1759-1808. Memorandum: autograph manuscript, [no place] [between 1806-1808?], (566); 1s.
  Memorandum on John Bilstone's edition of Thomas Hearne. With an autograph endorsement signed by William Upcott, who worked under Porson from 1806 onward.
- Porter, Lucy, 1715-1786. Autograph letter, signed, Lichfield (England), to her stepfather Samuel Johnson, 1780 Apr. 15., (567); 2s.
  Discusses the health of Henry Thrale and the fashion sense of his daughter, later Hester Maria Elphinstone, Viscountess Keith. With typescript transcript.
- Portland, William Henry Cavendish-Bentinck, Duke of, 1738-1809. Autograph letter, signed, Bulstrode [Buckinghamshire, England] to [Robert Stewart, Viscount Castlereagh] 1800 Mar. 12., (568); 1s.
  Concerning the proposed union of Ireland with Great Britain.
- Portland, William Henry Cavendish-Bentinck, Duke of, 1738-1809. Autograph note, [no place] to Edmond Malone, 1790 Nov. 19., (569); 1s.
  Thanks for Malone's edition of William Shakespeare.